



IT professional capable of advanced scripting on different languages from concept to completion of projects. Strong analytical skills combined with experience on application development, web development, mobile development, project tests and implementation. Excellent communication skills. Fluent in English, Hindi, and Nepali.

TECHNICAL SUMMARY

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, SQL

Technologies and Frameworks: ReactJS, React Native, Node.js, ExpressJS, BackboneJS, Ruby on Rails, jQuery, Github, GitFlow, VanillaJS, sendGrid API, Dwolla API, Bing API, Plaid API, Stripe API, Google API, Facebook API, Ajax, express-sessions, rails-sessions, handlebars, sockets.io, heroku, Bootstrap, CSS3, HTML5, postgreSql, Sass, AngularJS, mongodb, three.js, wordpress

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AnalogMethod.com, New Jersey (Jun 2016 – current): Full Stack Developer

- Built and maintained full stack application with Node is using financial APIs, unit testing, and deployed app in AWS.
- React front-end with Postgres database integration and developed schema mapping
- Integrated a payment and verification system, as well as a backend financial operations system to manage withdrawals
- Created subscription payment systems, supported by a daily cron script.

Kidpass.com, New York (Feb 2016 – Jun 2016): Full Stack Developer

- Deployed code after unit testing ReactJS in karma and webpack. Implemented A/B Test
- Built location services integration with google and added facebook api for login.
- Integrated stripe payments using Node is and helped build supporting features for an admin panel

Rutgers Coding Bootcamp, Jersey City(August 2015 -June 2016): Full Stack Developer Teacher's Assistant

- Helped tutor a class of 80 students in an intensive full stack web development course.
- Helped grade homeworks by looking through code bases for errors and optimization gaps.
- Taught the class directly on targeted code projects specified by the instructor, react-native was my course.

Freelance Work Experience, New York (Aug 2015 - Current): Full Stack Web Developer

- Built a single page ROR feature for the client's web application using Angular.js, Ruby, jQuery
- Integrated an Angular modal feature to display individual modals of the respective items.

skincarex.herokuapp.com

A single page e-commerce app focused on a pharmaceutical company and their products built in Backbone.js using Node.js with Express and PostgreSQL.

- Built a shopping cart system using jQuery and Ajax
- Rendered a 3D model to demonstrate structure of the main ingredient of the product using three.js
- Implemented a real time chat feature using sockets io and integrated a contact email feature using sendGrid API

sosnowapp.herokuapp.com

A single page ROR application using Backbone.js that is aimed to help the victims of natural disasters by finding the victims using google maps geolocation when the victims sends out SOS messages.

- Integrated user authentication using rails sessions and bcrypt
- Displayed modal templates using Backbone.js and styled the application using CSS and jQuery
- Allowed users(volunteers) to customize a list of victims with a custom function in ROR

wicki.herokuapp.com

A multi-page application which publishes editable articles using Node is with Express and PostgreSQL.

- Rendered editable articles with handlebars using RESTful API routes
- Integrated user authentication using express sessions and bcrypt
- Maintained the data in handlebars using custom SQL queries in ORM

EDUCATION

General Assembly, New York, NY (Jun 2015 – Aug 2015)

Web Development Immersive | Web Developer

Advanced Python Workshop (practiced problems on list comprehensions, sets, lambda function, counter, etc)

Agile and Scrum: Dramatically Improving Software Delivery (learned to develop product in Agile way using Scrum)

Metropolitan State College of Denver — Denver, CO (2006 – 2010)-Bachelor of Science in Chemistry